Artifacts Register, 1879-[ongoing]
Smith College Archives
Artifacts Register
1879-[ongoing]
Smith College.
RG 200
31 boxes and oversize materials (27 linear ft.)
Smith College Archives Northampton, MA
The College Archives is home to over six hundred artifacts which supplement the documentary and photographic history of Smith College. The Artifacts Collection includes Smith College, class, and club pins and jewelry, Reunion paraphernalia, house banners and t-shirts, samples of the Smith Wedgwood china, Smith College Relief Unit mementos, souvenirs from special events, and countless other objects.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The College Archives is home to over six hundred artifacts which supplement the documentary and photographic history of Smith College. They range in date from 1879 to the present; some cannot be precisely dated. The Artifacts Collection includes Smith College, class, and club pins and jewelry, Reunion paraphernalia, house banners and t-shirts, samples of the Smith Wedgwood china, Smith College Relief Unit mementos, souvenirs from special events, and countless other objects-many of which resist easy categorization.
Arrangement of the Collection
Every artifact has been assigned a Registration Number. It is used to catalogue and assign a location to the artifact, and bears no relation to the type of artifact, its date, or the date of its acquisition. The register is arranged numerically by registration number. Because of this, the paper copy of the register is useful largely for casual browsing, and the keyword-searchable computer file should be used for directed searches.
The following abbreviations are used in the register:
Bx = Artifacts Box
Pn = Pin/Jewelry Box
Ft = Flat Box
LDC = Lounge Display Case
LSC = Lounge Spoon Case
Sm = Small Box
A91 or A91a = Archivists' Offices
Jnx = Joannex (for objects too large to be boxed)
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The collection is open to researchers according to the regulations of the College Archives. Any material relating to the addresses of the artifacts' donors is restricted.
Additions to the Collection
Periodic additions to the collection are expected.
History of the Collection
The artifacts in the Register were donated by various sources over a long period of time.
Search Terms
Smith College--Collectibles.; Smith College--History--Sources.; Smith College--Miscellanea.; Smith College--Uniforms.; Smith College--Artifacts.
- Sash and buckle/c. 1910, 1; 5"x8" metal and cloth
  From Class of 1910, red striped.
  Belonged to Elsie Irwin Sweeney 1910
  fine
- Award Plaque/1972, 2; 4.5" x 6.5" metal
  Grand Award to SC for Excellence in Advertising, given by Advertising Club of Springfield, MA.
- Alumnae Asso. Centenntial Scarf/1981, 3; 20"x20" cloth
  Green print blocks on white background.
  small area discolored; fine
- Women Presidents' Summit Pin/1990, 4; 0.75"x1" metal, enamel
  Received by Pres. Dunn at American Council on Education, Dec. 1990. White and purple design, gold trim.
  excellent
- SC Ring/1911, 5; 0.75" across metal
  SC Insignia bordered by flower on each side.
  Belonged to Minerva King 1911
- Miniature Silver Mug/1881, 6; 1"x 1.25" silver, cord
  Favor from Class of 1885 Sophomore Reception for Class of 1884 in Social Hall, 5 October 1881. Blue and brown cord attached. See accompanying documentation.
- Medal from City of Bruges, Belgium/1974, 7; 2.25" across metal, gold-plate
  Depicts two figures against city scene. Presented to Smith College Chamber Singers on their 11th European Tour.
  gold-plate eroding
- Smith Spoon/N.D., 8; 4.5", 1" bowl sterling silver
  Silver, tip of handle features SC insignia.
- Plaster Medallion/N.D., 9; 4.25" across plaster
  Profile of Ruth Huntington 1897.
  some small chips; okay
- City of Northampton Mayor's Key/N.D., 10; 6.5"x1.5" metal
  Awarded to Persis Putnam 1911. Red string attaches identification card to key.
- Key to Dade County, Forida/N.D., 11; 7"x2.5" metal
  Given to Pres. Mendenhall.
- Sophia Smith Associates Centennial Pin/1975, 12; 2"x1.25" metal
  AASC. Pin is gold and in the shape of a cicada. See accompanying documentation.
- SC Relief Unit ID Bracelet/ c. 1917-1920, 13; ID 1" Chain 5" metal
  Inscribed with name "Dorothy A. Young." See accompanying documentation.
  Belonged to Dorothy A. Young; sent by Mrs. William C. Young.
- Mary Augusta Jordan Medal/ N.D., 14; 2" across bronze
  Image of MAJ on front; inscription on back: "Presented by the Alumnae of Smith College to _____ for the best original literary work of her class…" No name inscribed.
- Mary Augusta Jordan Medal/ 1928, 15; 2" across bronze
  Described under #14. Awarded to Anne Morrow. See accompanying documentation.
- Pendant/N.D., 16; 1.5" across 30" ribbon metal, cloth
  Pendant on yellow and white ribbon.
  Donated in Aug 1976 by F. MacDonald. Possibly belonged to Jane Crary 1934. ?
  pendant fine, ribbon stained
- SC Medallion/ N.D., 17; 4.5"x1.5" metal, cloth
  Inscribed to Florence Snow 1904. Hangs on black ribbon.
- Amelia Earhart Medallion/ N.D., 18; 1.25" across metal
  Image of Earhart on front, inscription on reverse. From the "Medal of the Month" series. See accompanying documentation.
  Belonged to Felicity Buranelli. Donated in 1978 by Gloria Heath 1943.
- SC Seal/N.D., 19; 5"x4" wood, metal
  Seal mounted on wood wall crest.
- Nails/N.D., 20; 2.5" each metal
  Two nails from Eleanor Duckett's house. ?
  rusty
- Diploma Ring/1895, 21; 1" across 0.75" wide copper?
  Metal ring inscribed with "Annie E. Paret Smith College June 13, 1895" and "God bless this parchment".
- Reconnaissance Francaise Medal/1920, 22; 1.25" across 2" ribbon metal, cloth
  Silvery medal on white ribbon trimmed in red and blue with blue star. On front of medal: 2 figures. Back is inscribed "Reconnaissance Francaise". Medals were awarded by the French government to "Vaillantes Femmes du Smith College" for WWI service in France (Smith College Relief Unit). Recipient of this particular medal unknown.
  tarnished
- Junior Promenade Dance Cards/ 1913, 23; 2.25"x1 0.75" each metal, paper
  Booklets (two) are metal-bound with paper pages. Names are written in for various dances. One attached to cord for wear around neck.
  Belonged to Mrs. Harry H. Motheral.
- Stamp Box/ 1900, 24; 1.25"x1" metal
  SC stamp box containing one stamp of later print. Metal box, opens on top. Inscribed with "SC 1900". In leather bag. See accompanying documentation.
  From Mary E. Wiley 1900.
- Pace University Medallion/1983, 25; 2.5" across 32" ribbon metal, cloth
  Medallion on blue and yellow ribbon. Presented to Gladys Sperrle 1930 on occasion of Pace U. Golden Anniversary. Inscribed: "Responsible Participation in an Economy of Free People".
  87A-88
- SC Belt Buckle/ N.D., 26; 3.5"x3" metal
  Stylized SC on metal buckle.
  From Minerva King 1911.
- Christening Bottle "Label"/ 1945, 27; 4.5"x2.5" metal
  Inscribed "S.S. Smith Victory".
- Library Plaque/N.D., 28; 8.25"x5.25" wood, metal
  Inscribed in memory of Margaret May Ward 1915 or 1924. ?
  From library.
- Reconnaissance Francaise Medal/1920, 29; 1.25" across 2" ribbon metal, cloth
  Described under #22. Bestowed upon Frances Wadsworth Valentine 1902.
- Lanning Fountain Engraving/N.D., 30; 8"x10.25" metal
  See accompanying documentation.
  okay
- SC Seals/N.D., 31 a-c; 3: 1.25" metal, cloth
  Three SC Seals with black ribbon attached.
- SC Seal Watch Fob/N.D., 31d; 1.25" across 3.5" long silver
  Seal on short fob chain. Motto in gold on white around edge.
- SC Seal/N.D., 32; 2 1/8" across metal
  Round. See accompanying documentation.
  Found in the earth at Wenham, MA on farm owned by Mr. /Mrs. Edward H. Osgood (Margaret Nickerson 1912).
- Sophia Smith Change Dolls/N.D., 33; 6.5"x4" cloth
  Three black velvet and one black crepe Sophia Smith "change dolls" each w/ small sign reading, "Change Sophia to stand up for Smith". Used by the Cleveland Smith Club.
  some fine; others worn
- SC Staff Bicycle Plate/ c. 1930, 34; 3" across metal
  Round; black with white lettering.
  87A- 114
- Historic Elm Plaque/ ?, 35; 4"x6" metal
  From Elm Research Institute, designating President's Elm an historic landmark
  87A-138
  letters running
- SC Ribbons/ N.D., 36; 6.5"x1.25" 7"x2.5" 6"x2" cloth
  Two red ribbons, "SCPC" on each. Probably Sophomore Push Committee ribbons. One white ribbon, "Smith" in gold. Usage unknown.
  reds fine; white very dirty
- Grass Cops Badge/N.D., 37; 2 1/8"x1 0.75" metal
  Shield-style badge inscribed with "Grass Cops". Silver.
- Medal of Vicenza, Italy/1965, 38; 1.5" across metal
  Depicts plaza on front and "Commune di Vicenza" on reverse. Presented to each conductor of the Smith/Princeton Chamber Chorus on 1965 European tour. See accompanying documentation.
- SC Medal/1979, 39; 2.5" across bronze
  Designed by art professor Leonard Baskin, the medal features an owl on one side and a representation of wisdom on the other. Inscribed to Iva Dee Hiatt; presented May 18, 1979.
- Key to Cincinnati, OH/ N.D., 40; 4"x2" metal
  Presented to President Conway by the mayor of Cincinnati.
  foam packing stuck to back
- Metal Plaque/N.D., 41; 2.25"x5" metal
  To library from a Boston alum (1909). ?
  semi-okay
- Reconnaissance Francaise Medal/1920, 42; 1.25" across 2" ribbon metal, cloth
  Described under #22. Bestowed upon Marie L. Wolfs 1908.
- Reconnaissance Francaise Medal/1920, 43; 1.25" across 2" ribbon metal, cloth
  Described under #22. Not known upon whom this medal was bestowed. Note: in original case.
  tarnished/ dirty
- China Shard/N.D., 44; 5"x2 1/8" china
  Shard of Sophia Smith Homestead china. White with blue flowered border. Pattern purchased by Alumnae Association after purchase of Homestead. Pattern is "Oakworth" by Jones, McDuffee, & Stratton.
  fine, for a shard
- Peacock Beads/ N.D., 45; 14.5" long glass
  Used at a reunion by Elizabeth Lawrence Clarke 1883. ?
  From ELC's daughter Elizabeth 1916.
- Ashtray/1907, 46; 4"x4" ceramic
  White with blue figuring. Inscribed with "Augusta Perusia" and the class mascot of 1907.
- Tile/1907, 47; 5"x5" ceramic
  White with blue figuring. Inscribed with "Augusta Perusia" and the 1907 class mascot.
- Stamp of SC Seal/N.D., 48; 1 5/8" across metal, wood
  Stamp mounted on wood.
- Stamp of SC Seal/N.D., 49; 3.25" across metal, wood
- Kerchief Squares/N.D., 50; 8"x8" cloth
  Two hand-blocked squares. Designed and wrought by Louise T. Kenyon. Green design depicting Ivy Day and Commencement on white background. See accompanying documentation.
- Linnaen Society Wax Seals/N.D., 51; 1.5" each wax, paper, cord
  Three red wax seals bearing coat of arms of Linnaen Society of London. Possibly related to Blakeslee Award (see #59).
  2 fine, 1 broken
- Large Mary Augusta Jordan Medal/N.D., 52; 5" across metal
  Bronze. Made by Alice Morgan Wright. Perhaps model for AASC MAJ medal (described under #14)?
  surface appears mottled
- Columbia University Paperweight/ 1954, 53; 4"x2.25" metal
  Seated figure on front; King's College Crest on reverse. Inscriptions on both sides. Given to Marjorie Nicolson (SC professor of English) on occasion of Columbia's Bicentennial (1754-1954).
  a bit tarnished; greening
- Johns Hopkins Society of Scholars Medallion/1975, 54; 3" across bronze
  Crest on front; inscription to Marjorie Hope Nicolson on reverse. Awarded to MHN May 23, 1975.
  a bit discoloured
- Wilbur Lucius Cross Medal/ 1967, 55; 2 0.75" across bronze
  Image of WLC on front; inscription on reverse. Awarded by Yale Graduate School Asso. to Marjorie Hope Nicolson June 12, 1967.
- Carnegie Art Institute Medallion/1899, 56; 3.5" across metal
  Front depicts head with avian headdress and phrase "Honos alit artes". Reverse depicts two female figures, laurel wreath, and inscription. Awarded to Dwight W. Tryon for oil painting. See accompanying documentation.
- Miniature Seelye Portrait/ 1910, 57; 3 1/8"x2.25" bronze
  Replica of bronze portrait of Pres. Seelye by Alice Morgan Wright 1904, presented by the Class of 1904 for John M. Greene Hall on the retirement of Pres. Seelye in 1910. (From accompanying documentation.)
- Dissecting Implements/ c. 1894, 58; 7"x2.25" (case) wood, metal, plastic
  Includes scissors, suction tube, scalpel, tweezers, wooden case. See accompanying documentation.
  Belonged to Alice Evangeline Hall 1894.
  okay; box is broken inside
- Linnaen Society Medallion/1953, 59; 2 3/8" across pewter
  Image of Mistruzzi and "Francis cus redi" on front and "Omaggio del l'Istituto Superiore di Sanita Roma". Awarded to Albert Blakeslee (see 42. Faculty) for work in microbiology September 7-12, 1953.
- Hand-decorated Fan/c. 1895, 60; 13.5" long paper, wood
  Fan decorated by Ethel Fifield 1895 with cutouts from blue tone photos on one side and misc. cutouts on the other.
  88A-70
- Loving Cup/N.D., 61; 9"x9" silver
  Award given to Carlotta Greeug from Class of 1901.
  a bit tarnished
- Small Box/N.D., 62; 2 3/8" x 1.5" x 1 5/8" wood
  Blue flowered box given by Elizabeth Cutter Morrow to Class of 1896 at a reunion. ?
- Hand-decorated Fan/c. 1903, 63; 12" long paper, wood
  Decorated by ? Booker 1903 with cutouts on both sides. Trimmed with red ribbon and brown cord.
- Hand-decorated Fan/c. 1897, 64; 14.25" long paper, wood, metal
  Decorated by Agnes Jeferies 1897 with cutouts on one side, black on reverse. Trimmed with buttons and brown cord.
  From Agnes Jeferies.
- Wallace House Name Plate/ N.D., 65; 11"x3" metal
- Smith Banner/ N.D., 66; 31"x16.5" cloth
  Purple felt with beige "Smith" letters.
- no artifact, 67
- Basketball Hall of Fame Cup/ 1985, 68; 3.25"x2 0.75" ceramic
  Small cup marking 1985 induction of Senda Berenson into Basketball Hall of Fame.
- Sophia Smith's Ring/N.D., 69; 7/8" metal, stone
  Cameo set in gold with surrounding diamond (?) chips.
- SC Medal/1968, 70; 2.5" across metal
  Described under #39. Awarded to Margaret Storrs Grierson October 23, 1968.
- SC Medal/N.D., 71; 2.5" across metal
  Described under #39. No inscription.
- Pen and Pen Holder/1903, 72 a&b; 7 3/8"x 2 3/8" wood, metal
  Inscribed to secretary of E.M. Howe and F.M. Cushing, November 12, 1903.
- Great Blue Heron Trivet/ c. 1984-1989, 73; 6 0.75"x6.5" ceramic
  White with image of blue heron. Appreciation gift for Smith Capital Campaign 1984-1989. See accompanying documentation.
- Paperweight/ 1883, 74; 5"x 1 0.75"x3" wood
  Block of wood with "'83" painted on top.
- Blakeslee Medal ?, 75
- Pincushion/ N.D., 76; 3.5"x3" cloth
  Red, white, and blue heart-shaped pincushion.
  From Alison Pardee. ?
- University of Michigan Anniversary Medal/N.D., 77; 2 0.75" across metal
  Awarded to Marjorie Hope Nicolson.
  From MHN.
- Miniature Seelye Portrait/N.D., 78; 3 1/8"x2.25" bronze
  Described under #57.
- Miniature Seelye Portrait/N.D., 79; 3 1/8"x2.25" bronze
- Pan-American Exposition Medal/N.D., 80; 2.5" across metal
  Awarded to Dwight Tryon.
- Phi Beta Kappa Key/c. 1915, 81; 5.5"x1.5" metal, cloth
  Standard Phi Beta Kappa Key on black ribbon. See accompanying documentation.
  Belonged to Katharine S. Pearce 1915.
- Pocket Watch/N.D., 82; 2" across metal, glass
  Watch belonging to John M. Greene. Maker: Elgin.
- Mary Augusta Jordan Retirement Medallion/1921, 83; 2" across bronze
  Made by Alice Morgan Wright 1904. See accompanying documentation.
- Northampton Tercentenary Medallion/1954, 84a; 3.5" long 1.25" across nameplate 2 1/8" wide metal, cloth
  Pewter medal on red, white, and blue ribbon with nameplate at top. "Mrs. M. Grierson" in nameplate. Medal features Calvin Coolidge on front and Northampton symbols on reverse.
  Belonged to Margaret Storrs Grierson.
- Northampton Tercentenary Pin/1954, 84b; 1.25" across metal
  White with blue print; features Northampton symbols (same as back of medallion-see #84a).
  rusty; missing clasp
- Class of 1929 Reunion Dolls/ 1949, 85 a&b; 8"x3.25" ea plastic, cloth
  Two dolls-one blonde and one brunette-dressed in white satin dresses with yellow aprons. For 1929's 20th.
- Vest/1949, 86; 18"x15.25" cloth
  For Class of 1929's 20th Reunion. Yellow.
- Plaque/N.D., 87; 5 3/8"x3.5" paper
  Plaque bearing name of Dorothy Howard Goode (Malone).
  From old library. ?
- Banjo Club Pin/N.D., 88; 5/8" across metal
  Circular pin featuring a banjo.
- Biological Club Pin/N.D., 89; 0.75" long metal
  Diamond-shaped with gold stripes on black.
- Blue Pencil Club Pin/N.D., 90; 0.5" metal
  Two Greek letter Gammas.
- Clef Club Pin/N.D., 91; 7/16" metal
  Clef and letter "C" intertwined.
- Colloquium Club Pin/N.D., 92; 3/8" metal
  In shape of a pestle.
- Class Ring/N.D., 93; 0.75" metal
  (Inscription illegible.)
- Current Events Club Pin/N.D., 94; 0.5" across metal
  Map of Western hemisphere in gold on black.
- Debating Union Pin/N.D., 95; 11/16" metal
  Compressed "D" superimposed on elongated "U".
- Delta Sigma Pin/N.D., 96; 5/16" metal
  Greek letters Delta and Sigma.
- Flying Club Pin/N.D., 97; 1 1/16" metal
  Wings and circle inscribed with "FSC".
- French Club Pin/N.D., 98; 5/8" across metal
  Fleur-de-lis and words "La Societe Francaise".
- Poker Club Bracelet/N.D., 99; 2.5" wide metal
  Charm-style bracelet with four "cards" (one of each suit).
- Geology Club Pin/N.D., 100; 9/16" metal
  Depiction of fossil with chip in center. See accompanying documentation.
- German Club Pin/N.D., 101; 5/8" metal
  Oval with "SC" in center and "Deutscher Verein" on outside rim.
- German Club Pin/N.D., 102; metal
  Torch with "S" and "C" on either side and "Deutscher Verein" underneath.
- German Club Pin/N.D., 103; 0.5" metal
  Red, white, and blue shield with outline of bird in gold.
- AASC 50th Anniversary Medallion/1935, 104; 1.25" plus chain metal
- Glee Club Pin/N.D., 105; metal
- Greek Club Pin/N.D., 106; 0.75" x.5" metal
  Owl with outstretched wings.
- Greek Club Pin/N.D., 107; 5/8"x.25" metal
  Greek letters Sigma and Epsilon.
- Italian Club Pin/N.D., 108; 0.5" across metal
  Double circle with banner; banner inscribed "Il Tricolore".
- Italian Club Pin/N.D., 109; 0.75" across metal
  Blue shield on red and green circular background.
- Mandolin Club Pin/N.D., 110; 0.75"x9/16" metal
  Shape of a mandolin inscribed with "S.M.C.".
- Manuscript Club Pin/N.D., 111; 5/8"x.5" metal
  Shape of letters "MS".
- Mathematics Club Pin/N.S., 112; 1"x.25" metal
  Black-and-silver angled curve with that S-looking math thing.
- Olla Podrida Pin/N.D., 113; 0.75"x 0.75" metal
  Entwined letters "O" and "P" with black overlay in shape of a kettle.
- Omega Club Pin/N.D., 114; 2 3/8"x 3/8" metal
  Stick pin with Greek letter Omega at end.
- Oriental Club Pin/N.D., 115; 0.75" across metal
  Round-serpent with golden bird's head.
- Phi Kappa Psi Pin/N.D., 116; 0.75" across metal
  Three white panels with Greek letters Phi, Kappa, and Psi in gold. Round.
- Philosophy Club Pin/N.D., 117; 11/16" metal
  Black and gold featuring bust of ancient philosopher. ?
- Physics Club Pin/N.D., 118; 0.25"x3/8" metal
  Tiny coiled apparatus.
- Poison Ivy Society Pin/N.D., 119; 1"x5/8" metal
  Shape of three-lobed poison ivy leaf.
- Psychology Club Pin/N.D., 120; 7/16"x.5" metal
  Greek letter Psi in gold.
- Press Board Pin/N.D., 121; 3/8"x.5" metal
  Shape of ink bottle with "SC" and "PB" inscribed.
- Radio WCSR Pin/N.D., 122; 0.75"x 3/8" metal
  Shape of microphone with letters "WCSR" and "PBS" inscribed.
- Outing Club Pin/N.D., 123; 0.75"x.25" metal
  "SOC" in black letters on gold-and-white background.
- Smith College Monthly Pin/ N.D., 124; 2.25"x.25" metal
  Gold feather inscribed with "SCM".
- Smith College Weekly Pin/ N.D., 125; 0.5"x 5/8" metal
  Letters "SCW" in gold on shield.
- Spanish Club Pin/N.D., 126; 5/8" across metal
  Round medallion featuring a lion.
- Studio Club Pin/N.D., 127; 5/8"x 5/16" metal
  Block letters "SCSC".
- Spectator Club Pin/N.D., 128; 0.5" across metal, stone
  Word "Spectator" in outline with green stone in center. Round.
- Telescopium Club Pin/N.D., 129; 5/8" across metal
  Zodiac signs on disc.
- Vox Club Pin/N.D., 130; 9/16" equi. metal
  Pyramid with cut-out letters "Vox".
- Voice Club Pin/N.D., 131; 9/16"x.5" metal
  Irregular letters "V" and "C" superimposed in gold outline.
- Zeta Club Pin/N.D., 132; 0.75" metal
  Octagonal; 3 Greek letters Sigma ? in gold on black.
- First Senior Pin/N.D., 133; 1" across gold, stones
  Owl with outstretched wings and gemstone eyes encircled by snakes, also with gemstone eyes.
- SC Pin/N.D., 134; 0.5"x 0.75" metal
  Gold diamond-shaped pin with "SC" in white enamel. See #411 for more information.
- SC Seal Pin/ N.D., 135; 0.5", 5/8", 0.75" across metal
  Seal in gold trimmed in white. (Three pins.)
- Alpha Society Pin/1881, 136; 9/16"x.5" metal
  Angular "A."
  Possibly belonged to Eleanor Larrison 1882.
- Class Ring/ 1920, 137; 0.75" metal
  SC seal, graduation year inscribed.
- Grass Cops Badge/N.D., 138; 2.5"x 2.5" metal
  Words "Grass Cops" and three stars on gold shield.
- S Pin/N.D., 139; 0.5"x 0.75" gold
  "Old English" letter "S". Awarded to outstanding athletes. See accompanying documentation.
- Creamer and Sugar Bowl Set/N.D., 140; 7.25" (sb) 6.25" (c) silver
  Sugar bowl with lid and creamer each engraved with SC Seal.
- Creamer and Tray Set/N.D., 141; 6.25" wide silver
  Engraved with SC Seal.
- Creamer and Sugar Bowl Set/N.D., 142; 6.25" wide silver
  Sugar bowl without lid and creamer both engraved with SC Seal.
- Cup/pre-1935, 143; 3.5" pewter
  Engraved with pictures of Forbes Library, College Hall, and L. Clark Seelye. Made in Germany. See accompanying documentation.
  Given by Annette O'Leary 1935.
- Compote/N.D., 144; 12" across, 8" high glass
  Shallow-bowled, stemmed, cut-glass compote cup.
- Fruit Cup/N.D., 145; 8" across, 8.5" high glass
  Stemmed, cut-glass fruit dish.
- Tea Glass/1883, 146; 4"x 2.5" glass
  Stemmed glass, engraved with "C" and "83". Was used to serve tea in S.F. Clarke's laboratory. Given to his wife upon marriage. See legend in box. See accompanying documentation.
- Gavel/pre-1900, 147; 8"x 2.5" wood
  Made from a piece of the train that carried Lincoln to Gettysburg. Presented to 1900 junior class president Elizabeth Porter Meier 1901.
- Christ Icon/ c. 1946, 148; 9.5"x 7" tin, other
  Representation of Christ in "curled" tin frame. Presented to Miss R. Young by Yugoslavian students in 1946. See accompanying documentation.
- Tray/1979, 149; 12" across silver
  Presented to Iva Dee Hiatt in 1979. Round.
- Small Tray/ N.D., 150; 6 0.75" across silver
  Round tray is inscribed: "Iglesia San Ignacio / Biblioteca Luis Angel Arango / Bogota, Junio 1971".
- SC Choir Commem. Dish/1965, 151; 8.5" across
  Silver and blue; inscribed, "Smith College Choir 1964-65".
- Bowl/1952, 152; 10"x 5.5" silver
  Given to houses from 1952 to 1959 by Sigma Xi Society for Science Second Honors.
- Ashtray/N.D., 153; 4 0.75" across ceramic
  Ashtray features College Hall in color on white.
- SC Paper- weight/N.D., 154; 3" across glass
  Sepia picture of College Hall under glass dome.
- Limoges Tea Bag Dish/ 1895, 155; 4.5"x 3" china
  Shape and design of leaf with gold edging. From 1895 3-piece set. See also Items 156 and 157.
- Limoges Demitasse Cup/1895, 156; 3"x 2" china
  White cup with green leaf pattern; gold handle and rim. From 1895 3-piece set. See also Items 155 and 157.
- Limoges Saucer/1895, 157; 4.5" china
  White saucer with green leaf pattern; gold edging. From 1895 3-piece set. See also Items 155 and 156.
- SC Candy Dish/ N.D., 158; 4.25" across 1" deep ceramic
  Features line drawing of College Hall and gold edging. Textured.
  coloration uneven
- Memento Jar/ 1898, 159; 3.25"x 2.5" silver
  "Ginger jar" shape with removable cap. "'98" engraved on cap.
- Trowel/1954, 160; 12 0.75" x 4 3/8" silver, wood
  Trowel used for laying date stone for Helen Hills Hills Chapel.
- Willow Ware Soup Tureen/ N.D., 161; 9.5" x 7" x 8" ceramic
  Blue Willow Ware pattern; includes cover.
- Candle Holder/N.D., 162; 6" x 4" metal, glass